[music]
[Instructor] Cool,
so we have all the right steps
to make our game end.
So when we hit
one of the Obstacles
coming into the Scene everything stops.
However, you can see this problem,
where we just have this
infinite number of obstacles
being created nonstop.
Lets see how many we can pile on.
I don't actually want to see that so,
what we're going to do is we're
going to fix that small problem just
because we don't want to keep creating
all these obstacles in the scene.
We just want it to stop entirely.
So that way our game doesn't
just slow down to a stand still
because there's, a thousand
of these little obstacles
all the way over here
that you can't see.
So we're going to go
to our SpawnManager Script,
and using the same thing
that we just did
in our MoveLeft Script,
we're just going to get
another reference
to our PlayerController Script.
So if we make another private...
PlayerController...
and we'll call
this "playerControllerScript."
Now in our Start() method
we're going to attach our variable
to the reference of our
playerControllerScript in the Scene.
So we playerControllerScript,
we're going to set that to...
a GameObject
that we're going to Find("")
in our Scene
which happens to be called Player.
And then in Player,
we're going to find the Component
which is our PlayerController.
Now in order to stop
spawning our obstacles,
now that we have a reference
to our Player,
we're actually going to check
for when the game is over
inside of our SpawnObstacle() method.
So if we use an if() statement,
if() our PlayerControllerScript...
gameOver...
boolean...
is false, then we can just
cut this little bit out,
and paste it in our if()
statement.
So now when our gameOver is false
it'll keep creating all
of these Objects,
however when the game is over
then it stops creating these Objects.
Now if we save that,
and we double check in Unity,
you can see that our Player
hits our obstacle,
and none of the obstacles
are magically spawning
which is great.
So now it's our turn,
in your SpawnManager Script,
you're going to create another
PlayerController variable
in the Start() method
you're going to set
the playerControllerScript
variable
to the PlayerController Script
of our Player Object in our Scene.
And then to stop spawning
any of these obstacles
in our SpawnObstacle() method,
we're actually going to check
when the game is not over
to keep creating these obstacles.
Otherwise when the game is over
it'll skip over this line of code,
and it won't create any more obstacles.
Now it's your turn.
[music]